DAVID CARRIE

Software Engineer

David.carrie@gmail.com

Scarborough, Ontario

https://www.linkedin.com/in/davidcarrie/

Soon to be Software Engineering graduate with three internships involving software development and DevOps at PwC Canada. Experienced in developing solutions in an enterprise software environment. Self-starter and quick learner, with a strong desire to learn new skills and technologies. Excited to gain industry experience.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer Intern: DevOps Department

PwC Canada

May 2021 - Aug 2021

Toronto, Ontario

- Developed UI-Path (RPA) C# processes to automate workflows.
- Created and maintained documentation including software specifications.
- Participated in code and design walkthroughs.
- Investigated technologies in consideration by the department and provided demonstrations to the team.
- Provided solutions with various technologies to support staff. Such as creating Google scripts to interact with RESTful APIs and automatically process data.

Co-Op Student: Enterprise Project Management Office

PwC Canada

May 2018 - Aug 2019

Toronto, Ontario

- Created and maintained kanban project boards (Asana WMS) and an internal website (Google Sites) to support agile based project management.
- Used data analytic and visualization software (Alteryx and Tableau) to provide business intelligence in support of projects.
- Interviewed clients, analyzed and created business requirement documents.
- Attended daily stand-ups, maintained RAID logs, and participated in regularly scheduled team meetings providing updates and participating in discussions.

PROJECTS

Plant Buddy: Automated Plant Care System

Cross Functional Team Leader

September 2021 - April 2022

- Developed Arduino code (C++) for automation of control system.
- Led team meetings, communicated deliverables and deadlines effectively.
- Wrote and maintained extensive technical documentation.
- Responsible for designing physical aspects and hardware of the system including: power, hazard containment, sensors, and water and light delivery systems.

Tetris Tussle: Web-Based based 2 Player Game

Software Engineer

- Designed and maintained software modules responsible for game modelling.
- Designed, prepared, and conducted test plans for unit-testing using JEST.
- Implemented Node.js to facilitate internet play between two users.
- Used Doxygen for auto documentation, Git for source code control.
- Developed in Linux: Ubuntu.
- Utilized JavaScript and the P5.js processing library to create game visuals.

Education

Bachelor of Engineering and Management: Software Engineering GPA: 9.8/12 ~ 3.7/4 McMaster University 2023

Skills

Technical Skills

- Windows, Linux and Linux Ubuntu
- Microsoft Office and Google Suite
- Visual Studio, Visual Studio Code
- Git, and Git related platforms
- Alteryx and Tableau
- UiPath Platform

Programming Languages

- Java, C, C++, Python, JavaScript, Arduino
- Minor: C#, HTML5, CSS, jQuery, Bash, CLI, SQL